In the previous video, we introduced Cloud Skills to everyone
as well as the types of tasks it can assist us with
In today's video, I will guide you step by step
how to start from scratch and go from 0 to 1
create your first complete skills
Additionally, the approach we're demonstrating today
No programming background is required
you just need to follow my video
you do it once
you can then summarize your own methodology from this hands-on process
summarize your own methodology
Additionally, I'll also provide you with some
my completed cases as reference
For example, give it a report
It can help us convert it into web page information
just input the text into it
it can help us fit the content into the company's template
help us produce the finished slides
Or simply input the topic
It can help us draft the script in just 5 minutes.
Without further ado
Let's get started
For viewers who are not familiar with skills,
Let me summarize it in one sentence for everyone
Skills are folders in Cloud for storing workflows and data.
Then you can use it to build your workflow
So you just need to tell it your task
it can go to the backend and
invoke all relevant skill packages and data related to this task
help you get things done
Does it sound a bit confusing?
Perhaps many friends might say at this point
Are there any ready-to-use skills available?
You know what
There really is aerobic
The official team has open-sourced a skills repository themselves.
In this folder are the official Skills created by Cloud themselves.
I've also briefly organized their uses for everyone
The ones that are more recommended for installation are these few on the screen
These are almost universally useful for everyone.
First of all
Whether you're using Windows or Mac systems
cloud skills are compatible with both
Today, I will use the web version of Cloud to demonstrate for everyone.
Let's start with a simple example first.
This time, we'll use the preset skills in Cloud.
Suppose I am an employee working in the real estate industry
Now I have a report about the Reserve Bank of Australia
research report on the interest rate forecast for next week
Now I need to quickly organize this content
compile it into a webpage suitable for teaching my clients
allowing them to view it by clicking the link
get straight to the point
So we come to the Settings
Select the function here
scroll down
enable the preset theme same factory skills
By the way, let me mention
This skill is suitable for helping us create slide reports and webpages.
Now let's go back to the chat box
upload this research report
help us create a visually intuitive webpage
Look here
I didn't specifically specify
which of the ten preset themes it needs to use
but once it starts working
You can see ACLOUD automatically checks which skills
suitable for assisting us with this task
This is because we've already set it in the custom preferences here
have Cloud evaluate before each task
must evaluate which skills are most suitable
Similarly, this custom instruction
You can go to the Settings general section here in personal preferences
paste it here for him
It only took 2 minutes.
The webpage is now done.
Look, compared to those plain text webpages
Doesn't it look much easier to read?
Moreover, the theme color selected by Cloud for the webpage
It looks very professional
The key content has also been bolded and color-highlighted for us.
Finally, it also addresses potential interest rate hikes by the Reserve Bank
provided relevant strategy adjustments
I think as long as you master this technique
such as sales webpages or presentation slides
Now, let's try another example based on this.
Try another example
This time I'm asking it to help me draft
20 common questions list for this research report
Here are some requirements I put forward
Then, regarding all the details in the report,
generated potential questions that might be asked for us
very detailed response
In addition to being able to download it in markdown format
can also be exported as PDF
This way, it can also be shared with other team members.
We just gave you two examples
is to use the built-in skills of Cloud to assist with our work
you just need to provide Cloud with the relevant context
context and your requirements
it can then apply the corresponding skills to your workflow
Now you already know how to use the built-in skills in Cloud
However, if you haven't found
skills that suit your needs
You can also create new skills yourself
There are mainly two methods to create custom Skills
The first method is to extend existing official Skills
and then repackage it into a new Skills
For example, here I have a work-related PowerPoint template
I want to create a similar template in Cloud
so that it can be used directly for future work
without me having to input it repeatedly every time
Here we first upload the template to Cloud
First, let them read the official PowerPoint-making skills
Then create a new skill called SRLPPT
Here I strongly recommend that when creating new skills
provide Cloud with as much contextual information as possible
for example when to trigger the skills
What are the use cases
Which information remains unchanged
specific workflow
The most important thing is to ask him to refer to the original skills provided by the official.
avoid having our skills overlap with the official ones
Then output it into a directly usable file format
As you can see
Now CLAUA is reading the official PPT
Skills and Skill Creator
skill creator to understand the entire structure
Also, take a look at the PPT template I uploaded to extract visual elements from it
such as colors and fonts
It took about 5 minutes.
The new skills are now ready.
then we can download it
If we want to activate these newly created custom skills
simply go back to the Settings function
find your skills
then upload the skills we just created here
Now this custom Skill of ours
has been set up
we can then invoke it anytime in the chat
For example, I'm currently working on a
workflow-related slides
Then let Cloud extract key information from these materials for me
using the PPT skills I previously uploaded to it
Generate a 10-12 page slideshow for me
for internal training
You see here I specifically emphasized
using the Skills I created myself
to ensure that Cloud uses the template I just created
Now it's starting to invoke the skills I created
Analyze the structure of the PPT for me
design-generated content
At the same time, it will also refer to the official PPT design tips.
Now it starts creating the slides.
In just a few minutes, it's done for me.
We can download this slideshow
can also upload to Google Drive
Overall, it looks pretty good.
All the slides have a unified style
The theme and colors are exactly the same as the company's presentation template.
Although there are still some minor scripting and formatting issues
I have to make some minor adjustments myself
but most of the content is correct
The layout is also quite reasonable.
If you notice that Cloud is having issues with this task
encounter problems
or if you want to improve its output quality
you can continue to let cloud help you adjust the skills
and make updates
Although this feature is not yet 100% perfect
but to be honest, I think the sorting quality is quite good
After all, this is a task involving images and complex formatting.
Moreover, this method is not only suitable for presentations
Excel spreadsheets
landing pages and various other scenarios
So you don't need to build new skills from scratch
You can first try to utilize existing official Skills
expanding on its foundation
Next, let's take it a step further
that is, the second method
create new skills from scratch
and then integrate it with MCP
use it in a Cloud project
Let me give you an example
For example, I want to improve the efficiency of writing video scripts
improve
because over the past two years, I've been updating AI videos for everyone
So here I can use the connector to
connect Cloud to Me Google Drive
then in the middle dialog box
ask it to create a new skills for me
Here I will provide all the background information to it
have it incorporate the style of my previous verbatim scripts
At the same time,
I also specified the detailed writing instructions in the command
such as trigger mechanisms
how to retrieve content from the Knowledge base
Also refer to the presentation style in my video
Additionally, I have included the entire workflow in the instructions.
also includes the output format
because besides the video transcript,
I also want it to help generate corresponding titles for me
About and tags
This time it took quite a while
It took 7 minutes
generated this skills for us
We will download it
then upload it to the cloud
Now, let's assume that I want to, within the Cloud project,
Here we can tell him in the personal instructions at the top right corner
the output format I want
If you previously when customizing skills
some requirements
did not expect
You can also include those requirements that you didn't have time to mention earlier
put them all here
Additionally, we can also upload the previous video transcripts
upload to it
This way, it can also refer to it in real time
including the perspectives I want him to output content from
Note that I'm not limiting Cloud's ideas here
So I want to see
Can he extend additional content based on Me
You see here I also noted
Let it reference the skills I just designed
Here you don't need to write specific process details
Just specify which skills to use for what tasks.
At this point, CLAUDIA will first read the skills I designed
workflow and specifications
then analyze my speaking style characteristics
Then it organizes the key information and core functionalities of the moto bot
Then it started to help me draft the verbatim script.
Finally, it took just 5 minutes
wrote a 6,800-word script
As you can see
Cloud strictly followed the workflow I provided
helped me generate an upload
from the opening citation to the conclusion output
to introduce what MOTBT is
What can it do
how to deploy from scratch
other advanced configuration techniques
What are the potential risks and precautions
Finally, it's the summary and outlook
To be honest, seeing this output result
I was quite surprised
The content is very comprehensive.
In addition, we can also download this solution
or add it to the project
can also be downloaded in PDF format
If you have any additional content you'd like to add
You can also ask Cloud to help you make modifications in the dialog box at any time
Finally, I'd like to remind everyone
When we need to call the project and MCP tools
You'll notice that
skills often require adjustments and modifications
So whenever you invoke the tool
try not to use too many in a single workflow
use too many MCP tools
Keep it as simple as possible
So today you can follow the steps I just mentioned
open the Skill Creator together
then solidify the most repetitive task in your daily work
such as filtering hot news
or turn a bunch of links into summaries and insights
When you complete this CUSE
and the moment it starts running
you will understand
The value of skills lies in continuous invocation and adjustment
Starting tomorrow
you'll start wanting to do a second one
the day after tomorrow, you'll want to migrate all your workflows into it
If you're not yet familiar with Skills
want to understand what Cloud Skills really is in just 10 minutes
I have a video
has been organized for you in the simplest plain language
You can click here to view
OK that's all for this video
If you found this video helpful
Welcome to like and subscribe to the channel
See you in the next video